# Rishubh Parihar

email - rishubhp@iisc.ac.in, web - https://rishubhpar.github.io/

My research focuses on making vision-generative models more controllable by providing new interfaces to interact with these models. Along this theme, I have worked on several projects ranging from fine-grained image editing to mitigating biases in deep generative models and guiding generative models for synthetic data generation to train downstream models.

## Education

Indian Institute of Science, Bangalore

2021 onwards

Ph.D. student, Department of Computational Data Sciences

9.70/10

Indian Institute of Technology, Delhi

2014-2018

Bachelor of Technology (B.Tech) in Mathematics and Computing

8.51/10

## Relevant coursework

Deep Learning for Computer Vision, Advanced Image Processing, Pattern Recognition and Neural Networks, Computer Graphics, Advanced Deep Learning, Stochastic Models and Applications, Computational Methods for Optimization, Video Analytics

# **Publications**

[1] PreciseControl: Enhancing Text-to-Image Diffusion Models with Fine-Grained Attribute Control *R Parihar\**, *Sachidanand VS\**, *S Mani*, *T Karmali*, *R Venkatesh Babu* 

#### European Conference on Computer Vision (ECCV'24)

- [1] Text2Place: Affordance Aware Human Guided Placement
  - R Parihar, H Gupta, Sachidanand VS, R Venkatesh Babu
  - **European Conference on Computer Vision (ECCV'24)**
- [1] Balancing Act: Distribution-Guided Debiasing in Diffusion Models
  - R Parihar\*, Abhijnya Bhat\*, Abhipsa Basu, Saswat Mallick, Jogendra Kundu, R Venkatesh Babu
  - Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition (CVPR'24)
- [2] We never go out of Style: Motion Disentanglement by Subspace Decomposition of Latent Space
  - R Parihar, R Magazine, P Tiwari, R Venkatesh Babu
  - AI for Content Creation workshop (CVPRW'23)
- [3] Exploring Attribute Variations in Style-based GANs Using Diffusion Models
  - R Parihar, B Prasanna, R Magazine, Sarthak Vora, T Karmali, Varun Jampani, R Venkatesh Babu
  - Workshop on Diffusion Models (NeurIPSW'2023)
- [4] Strata-NeRF: Neural Radiance Fields for Stratified Scenes
  - Ankit Dhiman, R Srinath, Harsh Rangwani, **Rishubh Parihar**, Lokesh R Boregowda, Srinath Sridhar, R Venkatesh Babu
  - **International Conference on Computer Vision (ICCV'23)**
- [5] Everything is there in Latent Space: Attribute Editing and Attribute Style Manipulation by StyleGAN Latent Space Exploration
  - R Parihar, A Dhiman, T Karmali, R Venkatesh Babu
  - ACM Conference on Multimedia (ACMMM'22)
- [6] Hierarchical Semantic Regularization of Latent Spaces in StyleGANs
  - T Karmali, R Parihar, S Agrawal, H Rangwani, V Jampani, M Singh, R Venkatesh Babu
  - **European Conference on Computer Vision (ECCV'22)**
- [7] FabSoften: Face Beautification via Dynamic Skin Smoothing, Guided Feathering, and Texture Restoration
  - S Velusamy, R Parihar, R Prasad, A Rege
  - NTIRE workshop (CVPRW 2020)

For complete publication results, please visit my Google Scholar profile.

# Experience

#### Sharechat / Data Scientist

Nov 2020 - Present

#### Multi-Modal content understanding

- Developed a multi-modal click-bait detection model for videos incorporating features from audio, video, and text modalities
- Adapted semi-supervised learning framework to deal with small set of labeled data and implemented mean teacher approach
  to propagate labels from a small set of manually labeled data to a large unlabeled dataset
- Experimented with various state-of-the-art deep networks for feature extraction for audio and video modalities and deployed the model on cloud for MOJ application (short video platform) for real time inference.

#### Samsung R&D Institute Bangalore / Research Engineer

Jul 2018 - Oct 2020

#### Self-Supervised video representation learning

- Design a pretext task based on object motion boundary prediction for self-supervised representation learning from videos
- In the first stage, the network was trained on unlabeled videos from the UCF101 dataset or feature learning
- In the second stage, the network was fine-tuned on HMDB51 dataset for video action classification and video retrieval tasks
- Experimented with various state-of-the-art video architectures (S3D-G, TSM) and network training strategies

#### SingleTake: A core camera feature for Samsung Mobile devices

- Designed and developed a motion classifier built over TSM to classify motion energy and motion type for a given video
- Performed weight quantization and model-pruning to make the model suitable for near real time inference on mobile device
- Involved in the conceptualization, design, development and commercialization of SingleTake for Samsung Galaxy S20

### Face beautification module for Samsung mobile devices

- Designed a wavelet-based face editing algorithm for skin texture enhancement which removes the non-uniformities in skin region while retaining fine-grained texture and deployed it to a range of Samsung mobile devices.
- Worked on various face beautification modules like skin region segmentation, lip segmentation and blemish removal
- Our framework provided personalized beautification based on gender, age and skin type and achieved superior quality results in overall appearance as compared to competitor mobile devices

# Awards and Achievements •

- Achieved SGPA of 10 in the second semester of Ph.D. coursework
- Awarded **PMRF** (direct entry) in August 2021
- Best presentation award at EECS Symposium 2023, IISc in visual analytics cluster
- Secured All India Rank 373 in JEE Advanced 2014 among 1,50,000 aspirants
- IIT Delhi Semester Merit Award (top 7% of the batch) for meritorious academic performance in the eighth semester
- Received "Jury Special" award for Best Demo at NIPUN 2018 (an annual tech fair) at Samsung R&D Institute, Bangalore
- Received "Spot Award" for development and commercialization of Smart Beauty Solution for Samsung Galaxy S10